The Maze Was Just the Beginning.
Maze Runner: The Scorch Trials is a science fiction,
action, thriller film directed by Wes Ball.
Thomas and his fellow Gladers face their greatest challenge yet: searching for
clues about the mysterious and powerful organization known as WCKD.
Their journey takes them to the Scorch, a desolate
landscape filled with unimaginable obstacles.
Teaming up with resistance fighters, the Gladers take on WCKD’s vastly
superior forces and uncover its shocking plans for them all.
Thomas, played by Dylan O'Brien.
Teresa Agnes, played by Kaya Scodelario.
Newt, played by Thomas Brodie-Sangster.
Jorge, played by Giancarlo Esposito.
Minho, played by Ki Hong Lee.
Frypan, played by Dexter Darden.
Maze Runner: The Scorch Trials (stylized onscreen simply as The Scorch Trials) is a 2015 American dystopian science fiction
film based on James Dashner's 2010 novel The Scorch Trials, the second novel in The Maze Runner book series.
The film is a direct sequel to the 2014 film The Maze Runner and the
second installment in The Maze Runner film series.
It was directed by Wes Ball, with a screenplay by T.
Adding to the original film's cast of Dylan O'Brien, Ki Hong Lee, Thomas Brodie-Sangster, Patricia Clarkson, Kaya Scodelario, Dexter
Darden and Alexander Flores, the new supporting cast includes Giancarlo Esposito, Aidan Gillen, Barry Pepper and Lili Taylor.
The plot of The Scorch Trials takes place immediately following the previous installment, as Thomas (O'Brien) and his fellow Gladers have
just escaped from the facilities of the powerful World Catastrophe Killzone Department (WCKD), which had imprisoned them.
On the run in the desert and ruined cities, they must escape WCKD soldiers and face the
perils of the Scorch, a desolate landscape filled with dangerous obstacles.
Filming began in Albuquerque, New Mexico on October 27, 2014,
and officially concluded on January 27, 2015.
Maze Runner: The Scorch Trials was released in select international territories starting September 9, 2015, in 2D, 3D, 4DX and Barco Escape,
and was released on September 18, 2015, in the United States in 2D and premium large-format theaters by 20th Century Fox.
It was originally set to be released in IMAX, but this was canceled, except Japan (converted to 3D), as
Everest had all worldwide IMAX screens booked until the release of the film The Walk.
The Scorch Trials received mixed reviews: some commended its action sequences and
performances; others criticized the film for its lack of plot and character advancement.
Like its predecessor, the film was a commercial success grossing $30.3 million on its
opening weekend, making it the ninth-highest grossing debut in September.
The film went to the number one spot at the box office during its
opening weekend, and grossed $312 million worldwide.
The concluding entry, titled Maze Runner: The Death
Cure, was released on January 26, 2018.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
escape, resistance, dystopia, maze.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.